KAYLA GELMAN

DATA ENGINEEING INTERN



kgelman01@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/kayla-gelman-108368147/

ABOUT ME

Approximately 32.3% of people studying a STEM degree are women. I am proud to be considered part of this figure, with a dream of transforming the world with AI and machine learning. I am a keen problem solver and I enjoy using my skills to solve real-world issues, particularly through hackathons. Through these experiences, I've learned to cope well under pressure and more recently, placed 1st in an Atlassian datathon.

SKILLS

Python

SQL

JavaScript

Tava

R C++

HTML/CSS

Advanced Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate

CO-CURRICULAR

UTS SPROUT

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

UTS Representative for Engineering and IT.

Women in Engineering and IT Ambassador

DECEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Class facilitator, educating primary and highschool girls on different streams of engineering

UTS Rocketry DevOps Team Lead

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

Primary role is to code and implement telementary devices to collect data from a rocket launch. Using tools such as Jira and Bitbucket to coordinate projects and deliver a final product by a set date.

UTS Engineering Society - Social Justice Exec

JULY 2020 - DECEMBER 2021

Assisted in organising industry and social events for students.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- UNSW x Atlassian Datathon (1st place)
- Data4Good Datathon (2nd place) 2020
- **UTS Lucy Mentoring Program**
- Women in Engineering and IT Cooperative **Scholar** 2019
- Code2Change Data/Coding Hackathon 2019

EXPERIENCE

Cyber Security Intern, Macquarie Group

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

Worked in a variety of roles within the Application Security Testing Team including but not limited to project management, security testing, and development. During this time, I managed the end-end testing process of 33 high-risk applications and automated a task of manually creating Jira tickets for upcoming applications due for a security assessment.

Associate Software Engineer, T-Shirt Ventures

JULY 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

Designed UI for an invoicing system using collaborative design tools such as Figma and maintained code for a middleware invoicing system using React and Node.js. Was also responsible for managing relationships with third-party clients to maintain the integration of an OCR API and ensured all systems were operating during work hours.

Group Technology Intern, Westpac

AUGUST 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

Assisted in a data profiling project in the Basel III data delivery team to identify issues with datasets used for credit risk machine learning models. Sourced data from SAS and exported it to R in order to create interactive visualisations for the wider team.

NDIS Plan Manager, Provider Choice

JULY 2019 - JULY 2021

Was responsible for the management of invoices and ensuring outstanding payment issues were resolved with empathy and care on hehalf of disabled customers

Cyber Security Intern, Woolworths

NOVEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

Co-ordinated a project which automated the import of SOL scripts and reports from various sources into one tableau dashboard. This dashboard allowed the Security Services & Identity Management team to identify key issues, improving overall operations.

EDUCATION

University of Technology Sydney

MARCH 2019 - NOVEMBER 2023 (EXPECTED)

B. Engineering (Honours) Data Engineering, Diploma in Professional Practice. 85.60 WAM

HOBBIES

Travel | Arduino | Coding | Drawing | Running